Najib M. VALEYEV

+351913891844 · NAJEEBENGINEERING@GMAIL.COM LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/najeebengineering

Engineering leader with proven skillset of automating complex processes and troubleshooting machinery issues. Combining technical expertise in mechanical design, electronics and 3D modeling with strong problem-solving, communication and teambuilding skills essential to optimize workflows, manage team productivity, mitigate risks and deliver projects on schedule, with a strong soft skills to excel in engineering leadership roles.

ACADEMIA

Vilnius Gediminas Technical University

Master's in Aerospace Engineering | 2022 - Present | Mobility at **University of Beira Interior** (UBI) Graduate Project:

UAV Radio Frequency Anti-Tampering Solutions.

National Aviation Academy

Bachelor's in Aerospace Engineering | 2018 - 2022

Graduate Project:

Development of micro-satellite's load-bearing structure.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oct 2019 - Present

KHALITOV ENTERPRICES INC

Software Developer

Facilitate the realization of bespoke, feature-rich and production-ready solutions that effectively address unique organizational challenges and fulfill strategic objectives defined by clientele.

Accomplishments:

- Prototyped a complete digitalization solution to fit the complex, and compliance essential sector.
- Elaborated a simple and incomplete expansion plan with establishment of a coherent web resource.
- Assembled and arranged an Internal Resource Management tool using mainly JavaScript, providing an immense productivity increase, as well as, an expanded field of customer reach for the authorised staff.
- Developed and maintained customer mobile application, where I demonstrated Full-Stack programming skills using Flutter, JS, Swift, Kotlin.
- Allocated a full-fledged back-end server for all customer services, secured their data, and added monetisation system into the ecosystem.
- Implemented various API services across platforms and programming languages in use for the whole digital HR management suite.

ETI (Naval Architecture Bureau)

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

Automation Engineer

Taken an innovative and novel approach to assist Naval Architects optimize hull design.

Accomplishments:

- Lead a CI/CD cycle implementation into a manufacturing processes of a composite vessel.
- Utilized CAD software along with FEM techniques to simulate and predict vessel's performance.
- Proposed a set of viable solutions to drastically increase the capabilities of the vessel in case of vessel operation contingencies.

ECOLO BLUE BAKU Sep 2021 - Oct 2021

Marine Coating Engineer Assistant

Provided technical assistance and support to marine engineers in assessing coating conditions, recommending coating specifications, and implementing coating strategies for a composite vessel.

Accomplishments:

- Researched and validated new paint and coating solutions including cleaning, pre-treatment, base-coat, and top-coat.
- Set up networks with coating solutions suppliers to select and conform coatings and coating systems to match the needs of both R&D requirements and workshop facility capacities.

Automation Engineer Assistant

Leveraged automation and digitization to improve the efficiency and performance of systems and processes.

Accomplishments:

• Implemented Electrical Automation acumen to increase overall conformity of operations to safety protocols, furthermore allowing better workplace satisfaction for colleagues.

CONDUCTED PROJECTS

Aeronautical Field

TeknoFest by T3 & Bayraktar Planed UAV Sailplane missions by assessing budget requirements, preplanning equipment needs, and generating comprehensive roadmaps to ensure successful execution.

- Strategically planning missions
- Assessing budgets
- Preplanning equipment
- Generating roadmaps
- Running overload tests on the UAV
- Performing a review & resetting of the initial flight control unit presets
- Successfully running the mission in an unanticipated frequency contingency
- Preparing a presentation plan with feedback gathering.

Marine Field

Mar&Ar Project Leading a team of 3 to enhance an efficiency of commercial delivery drones.

- Outlined a Basic concept
- Followed training manuals to cohere to a given project development approach
- Employed Research & Development skills to effectively integrate own research paper on BLI technology into the project, and started converting the theoretical concept into a potential startup.

Space Field

CANSAT

Lead R&D, Satellite design, for the development of a nano Satellite in collaboration with 2 Institutes.

- Guide technical development and decision-making across satellite systems disciplines, leading mission definition and design.
- Mentor team members and ensure the technical integrity of all contributions.

LABORATORY EXPERIENCE

LABORATORY TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST - TRIBOLOGY LAB @NAA

- Maintaining And Operating Laboratory Bruker UMT-2 equipment,
- · Optimizing measurement and data acquisition processes,
- · Producing Reliable Test Results and Analyzing them.

Primary equipment

- Bruker Corp. UniversalMerchanicalTester with a wide variety of Set-ups and Conditions.
- · Scanning Tunneling Microscope.
- Atomic Force Microscope.

QUALIFICATIONS

Intellectual Property Law Specialization Google Cloud
Application Development
Specialization

Full Stack Web Development Specialization

LANGUAGES & IT SKILLS

- English, Russian, Tatar, Azerbaijani, Turkish, Portuguese.
- Aerospace & Naval: STK, Ansys, Solidworks, Autodesk, Rocket Propulsion Analysis, Matlab, Proteus, Eagle CAD, Arduino, SCADA, Qt, SimScale.
- App Development: Dart/Flutter, HTML/CSS, JS, Kotlin/Java, C/C++, Swift, Python, Java.
- General: LaTex, UMT Suite.